SKILLS

ReactJs, TypeScript, Javascript

HTML - HTML5, CSS - CSS3, SASS

PHP (Yii2), Java, Scala, C#, Nodejs Python (Django)

AWS, Git, Jira, Bitbucket, Github, Jenkins, Instana.

PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB

Agile methodologies, TDD

Spanish: Native

English: c1

EDUCATION

Corporación Universitaria Americana Systems Engineering Barranquilla – Colombia

.NET Certificate Americana Barranquilla - Colombia

Elastix Elastix VOIP security. Bogotá - Colombia

INTERESTS

Technologies updating

Always looking for the latest technologies and being up to date with them.

Healthy life

Investigate what is the best for my health is like a passion, I am vegetarian and I love to know the things that can keep me with my Optimum wellness.

JOHN CALDERON

Systems Engineer

PROFILE

Full Stack engineer focused on frontend with 9 years of experience, using React, TypeScript, JavaScript as my current preferred technologies, and others like Nodejs, PHP and Python. With high skills on the best practices, agile development and user experience guidelines that exceed expectations. I like to understand flows, use cases and tools in my environment to provide the best solutions.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

2022 – 2024 Remote

LATAL SOFTWARE

Full stack Developer

Development role on a customer, working on

JavaScript/Typescript react, node and PHP projects for different e-learning platforms as services for customers.

Accomplished support tasks, did a frontend administrative tool,

helped with data migrations, worked on fixes and

improvements.

2021 – 2022 Remote

INSTALEAP

Full stack Developer

Development of Reactjs, Nodejs and TypeScript project for E-commerce administration tool that reduces support tickets and adds value for the customers.

Collaboration with a SCALA service for endpoints to manage

information with MongoDB and high traffic data. Management of team tools and agile methodologies.

2020 – 2021 Remote

ZITSEC

Development engineer and Software architect

Collaboration for the development of a visitor control software using Python with Django framework for backend, Reactjs for frontend and POSTGRESQL and MySQL for databases.

2017 – 2022 Remote

PASTEUR LABS

Full stack Developer

Development of the clinical laboratory ERP ConlabWeb 2.0 using PHP with Yii2 framework, JavaScript, DB POSTGRESQL and BITBUCKET. Internal management of company processes, direct contact with software end users and support on the tool. ConlabWeb 2.0 was the upgrade for ConlabWeb software, adding value to the lab in the different business areas and generating more profit.

Development of integration and interfaces with accounting software

Development of laboratory equipment communication interface using java, reactJs and PHP.

CONTACT

- Parranquilla Colombia
- **9** +(57) 314 511 8611
- in https://www.linkedin.com/in/john-calderon-zapata/